Gu Xiang Gaoyi
구샹가오이
Fengguzhengzheng
풍구정정
Li Shiqi admired him very much
Li Shiqi는 그를 매우 존경했습니다.
I'm so lucky to see you today
오늘 당신을 만나서 정말 행운이에요
Seventeen Lang is polite.
세븐틴랭은 예의바르네요.
I have long heard the legend in the military
나는 군대에서 전설을 오랫동안 들어왔다.
Talking about Seventeen Lang Young Toshihiko
세븐틴 랑영 토시히코에 대해 말하다
See you today
오늘 만나요
It is indeed well-deserved
참으로 그럴만한 가치가 있는 일이다
I don’t know that Seventeen Lang ventured into Beijing
세븐틴 랭이 베이징에 진출한지는 모르겠지만
What's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
Sun Jing overthrew the country
손징이 나라를 무너뜨렸다
To cause chaos
혼란을 일으키다
The world has been suffering from the thief for a long time
세상은 오랫동안 도둑으로 인해 고통을 받아왔습니다.
Please see Mr. Gu today
오늘은 구씨를 만나보세요
I just hope Gu Xiang
그냥 구샹이길 바랄 뿐이야
Able to contact Jingzhong
Jingzhong에 연락할 수 있습니다
A family of old ministers loyal to the country
나라에 충성하는 노대신 가문
Cooperate with our Zhenxi Army inside and outside
우리의 Zhenxi 군대와 내부 및 외부 협력
Recapture West Changjing
창징서부를 탈환하라
Sun Jing is treacherous and suspicious
Sun Jing은 배신적이고 의심스럽습니다.
Since the official affairs of Zheng Guo in Luoyang,
정국(鄭國)의 뤄양(洛陽) 공무 이후
He treated the old ministers and families of the DPRK
조선민주주의인민공화국의 낡은 장관들과 가족들을 접대하였다.
Very closely guarded
매우 철저하게 보호됨
Tell the truth
진실을 말하세요
If not today
오늘이 아니면
Seventeen Lang's ingenious arrangement
세븐틴랭의 독창적인 편곡
It's hard for me too
나도 힘들다
Where to meet Shishiro
시시로를 만날 수 있는 곳
The guest officer is looking at the ingredients.
손님 담당자가 재료를 살펴보고 있습니다.
guest officer
손님 장교
Look at our material
우리의 자료를 봐
For your own use
귀하의 사용을 위해
I'd rather buy it for my relatives at home.
차라리 집에 있는 친척들에게 사주고 싶네요.
guest officer
손님 장교
I'll just take a look
그냥 좀 살펴볼게
You can see our cloth
우리 천을 볼 수 있어요
The sales this year are also very good.
올해 매출도 매우 좋습니다.
guest officer
손님 장교
I'll just take a look
그냥 좀 살펴볼게
Siege is military
포위 공격은 군사적이다
As long as the old ministers and families in the city
도시의 옛 목사들과 가족들이 있는 한
Heart to the country
나라를 향한 마음
Just help secretly
그냥 몰래 도와줘
The army will enter the city slowly
군대는 천천히 도시에 들어갈 것이다
If no one in the city responds
도시에 아무도 응답하지 않으면
I'm just afraid that after the army enters the city,
다만 군대가 도시에 진입한 후에는
Instead there was chaos
대신 혼란이 있었다
So it’s important to the neighbors
그래서 이웃에게 중요한 것이
Various departments and bureaus
다양한 부서 및 국
We also need to rely on the noble families in the city
우리도 도시의 귀족 가문에 의지해야 해요
Otherwise, all vital aspects of people's livelihood will be destroyed.
그렇지 않으면 사람들의 생활에 필수적인 모든 측면이 파괴될 것입니다.
Will lose popular support
대중적 지지를 잃게 될 것이다
This is natural
이것은 자연스러운 일이다
It can be coordinated secretly
비밀리에 조율이 가능해요
Canglin Youfang Water Well in the City
도시의 창린 유팡 우물
Canal gates and many other key points
운하 문 및 기타 여러 주요 포인트
All within the neighborhood
모두 동네 안에 있어요
Everyone in the family
가족 모두
Each has its own private guard
각각은 자신의 개인 경비원을 가지고 있습니다.
By then
그때까지
I will definitely protect you first
반드시 내가 먼저 널 지켜줄게
Thank you, Mr. Gu
감사합니다, 구 선생님
It seems
것 같다
Seventeen Lang already has a plan in mind
세븐틴랭은 이미 계획을 세웠어요
With a plan to break the city
도시를 무너뜨릴 계획을 가지고
A little planning
약간의 계획
This kind of thing is very confidential
이런 일은 아주 비밀스러운 일이에요
One more person knows
또 한 사람이 알아요
Just one more risk
위험 하나만 더
There’s no need for Shikiro to tell me
시키로가 나한테 말할 필요는 없어
By the time
그때쯤에는
I will take care of myself
나는 내 자신을 돌볼 것이다
Seventeen Lang's arrangement
세븐틴랭의 편곡
Completed Shijuro
시쥬로 완성
Just do what you have been asked to do
요청받은 대로만 하세요.
If you don’t buy the ingredients?
재료를 사지 않는다면?
Don't disturb other distinguished guests
다른 귀빈을 방해하지 마세요
You think so?
그렇게 생각하시나요?
Step aside
비켜서 다
Where did this idler come from?
이 아이들러는 어디서 왔나요?
This one fits quite well.
이것은 꽤 잘 맞습니다.
Father
아버지
what are you doing
뭐하세요
I'm sorry, I'm sorry
미안해요, 미안해요
Two guest officers
게스트 임원 2명
Not paying attention for a moment
한 순간도 주의를 기울이지 않음
Let this rogue break in
이 불량배가 침입하게 놔두세요
Go, go, go
가, 가, 가
I can meet Gu Xiang today
오늘은 구샹을 만날 수 있어요
It can be considered a near miss
거의 실패라고 볼 수 있습니다
I have to thank you for that plan
그 계획에 대해 감사해야 해요
I can get a word of thanks from Shishiro
시시로한테 감사 인사를 받을 수 있어요
It’s considered a worthwhile trip for me.
그것은 나에게 가치 있는 여행으로 여겨진다.
Cool and refreshing bayberry tea
시원하고 상큼한 월계수차
Young Master, please have a pot
젊은 스승님, 냄비를 드세요
Remember our day
우리의 하루를 기억해
under the hut
오두막 아래
Drinking tea and cooking in the rain?
비오는 날 차를 마시고 요리를 하시나요?
Of course I remember
물론 기억해요
If this time
만약 이번에
Able to recapture West Changjing
창징서부를 탈환할 수 있음
Kill Sun Jing
순징을 죽여라
Until then
그때까지
Let's ride horses and enjoy traveling together
말을 타고 함께 여행을 즐겨요
I'm just afraid that time will come
다만 그 시간이 올까봐 두렵다.
His Royal Highness the Emperor is busy with government affairs
천황폐하께서는 정무로 바쁘십니다.
There are other important things
다른 중요한 것들이 있어요
I have already forgotten
나는 이미 잊어버렸어요
I still have an appointment with Leyouyuan.
나는 아직 Leyouyuan과 약속이 있습니다.
impossible
불가능한
No matter how busy or tired you are
아무리 바쁘고 피곤해도
I will never forget you
나는 결고 널 잊을 수 없어
Will never forget
결코 잊지 않을 것
An appointment with your Leyouyuan
Leyouyuan과의 약속
The emperor has ascended the throne
황제가 왕위에 올랐습니다.
The Holy Emperor has ascended the throne
성황제가 즉위하셨다
This slogan is well written.
이 슬로건은 잘 쓰여졌습니다.
Especially the part where you scolded me
특히 네가 나를 혼낸 부분은
If the thief doesn't die, why should the common people deserve it?
도둑이 죽지 않는다면 왜 서민들이 그런 일을 당해야 합니까?
The Governor forgives me
주지사는 나를 용서합니다
What sin do you forgive?
무슨 죄를 용서합니까?
I think it's very good
내 생각엔 아주 좋은 것 같아
Such strict palace restrictions
이처럼 엄격한 궁전 제한
Can actually put one
실제로 하나 넣어도 되지만
The dead King Liang secretly left the palace
죽은 양왕은 몰래 궁궐을 떠났다
then come back to life
그럼 다시 살아나
He can still ascend the throne and proclaim himself emperor in Dengdu.
그는 여전히 왕위에 올라 덩두(Dengdu)에서 자신을 황제라고 선포할 수 있습니다.
Such extraordinary ability
이런 남다른 능력
This mysterious method
이 신비한 방법
I have no idea
나는 전혀 모른다
After falling asleep tonight
오늘밤 잠들고 나면
Will my head be lost tomorrow?
내일 머리가 빠질까?
The Governor forgives me
주지사는 나를 용서합니다
those suspicious people
그 수상한 사람들
No interrogation required
심문이 필요하지 않습니다
Kill them all
그들 모두를 죽일
And those
그리고 그것들
The stubborn old minister of the former dynasty
완고한 전 왕조의 노장관
Also send troops
군대도 보내라
Bring them to the palace
그들을 궁궐로 데려가라
Lest they get ready to take action
그들이 조치를 취할 준비를 하지 않도록
yes
예
Grand Governor
총독
Should we close Ninetowns?
나인타운을 폐쇄해야 할까요?
No entry or exit for the public
일반인 출입 금지
Search carefully
신중하게 검색하세요
Since we sent people to West Changjing
우리가 서창징으로 사람을 보낸 이후로
Distribute slogans
슬로건 배포
Naturally, he wants to disturb the people's sentiments
당연히 국민의 정서를 어지럽히려는 의도다.
Why do you need to fall into their trap?
왜 그들의 함정에 빠질 필요가 있습니까?
Li Yi’s army approaches
리이(Li Yi)의 군대가 접근한다
Once the city is closed
도시가 폐쇄되면
The people were in chaos first
국민이 먼저 혼란에 빠졌다
detrimental to the war
전쟁에 해로운
The Governor is very worried
주지사는 매우 걱정하고 있습니다
but
하지만
People entering and leaving the city gate
성문으로 들어오고 나가는 사람들
Strict interrogation is required
엄중한 조사가 필요하다
The city must also be searched carefully
도시도 주의 깊게 수색해야 합니다
Be sure to catch those
그런 것들은 꼭 잡아라
The spy who circulated propaganda messages
선전 메시지를 유포한 스파이
beheaded them
그들을 참수했다
Send it to Luoyang
낙양으로 보내세요
Give that Liang Wang a good scare
Liang Wang에게 겁을 주라
The old man, King Liang, is timid
노인 양왕은 소심하다.
If you are really scared to death by me
나 때문에 정말 무서워 죽겠다면
That's it
그게 다야
What a big joke
정말 큰 농담이군요
yes
예
Stupid beyond reach
닿을 수 없는 바보
How stupid
얼마나 어리석은가
At this time, King Lin Er and King Xi Ji
이때 린얼왕과 서지왕이
Support Liang Wang to ascend the throne
Liang Wang이 왕위에 오를 수 있도록 지원
It's really not the time
정말 그럴 때가 아니다
I thought they
나는 그들이 생각했다
Kindly welcome father back
아버지의 복귀를 진심으로 환영합니다
I want to calm him down
그 사람을 진정시키고 싶어
It’s nothing more than an act of asking for credit
신용을 요구하는 행위에 지나지 않습니다
but i didn't expect
하지만 난 기대하지 않았어
They actually supported their father at this time
그들은 실제로 이때 아버지를 지원했습니다.
ascended the throne in Luoyang
낙양(洛陽)에서 즉위하다
And tell the world
그리고 세상에 말해요
so stupid
너무 멍청해
Jushichiro
주시치로
The situation is not good
상황이 좋지 않다
Sun Jing's troops
손징의 군대
Searching everywhere
어디서나 검색 중
A person who distributes propaganda messages
선전글을 유포하는 자
besides
게다가
when i just came back
내가 방금 돌아왔을 때
I heard the story is long
이야기가 길다고 들었는데
Send someone to tell the shopkeeper
사람을 보내서 가게 주인에게 알릴 것
All guests staying at the hotel
호텔에 투숙하는 모든 투숙객
All must be carefully inspected
모두 꼼꼼히 점검해야 합니다
Even if there is a store as a guarantee, it won’t work.
보증으로 매장이 있어도 작동하지 않습니다.
It seems that this place
아무래도 이 곳은
We can't live here much longer
우리는 여기서 더 이상 살 수 없습니다
Although we forged the survey
우리가 설문조사를 위조했지만
There is no difference between it and the real thing
실물이랑 별차이가 없네
But the neighbors in West Changjing
하지만 West Changjing의 이웃들은
Very strict control
매우 엄격한 통제
Just check carefully
잘 확인해보세요
You can still see it
아직도 볼 수 있어요
Our explorations are different
우리의 탐험은 달라요
Something bad happened
뭔가 나쁜 일이 일어났어요
I got the news
소식을 받았어요
The soldiers of the Forbidden Army surrounded the Gu Mansion.
자금군의 병사들이 구 저택을 포위했습니다.
I don’t dare to follow too closely either.
나도 감히 너무 가까이 따라갈 수는 없습니다.
Young Master
젊은 스승
Fortunately, General Pei
다행히 페이 장군은
The medicinal materials sent are very useful
보내주신 약재는 매우 유용합니다
Judging from pulse condition
맥박 상태로 판단
your injuries
당신의 부상
Already seven to eight points better
벌써 7~8점 더 좋아졌어
Waiting for the captain to come back
캡틴이 돌아오길 기다리고 있어요
we can set off
우리는 출발할 수 있다
Joined the army
군대에 입대했다
Young Master
젊은 스승
What's up
무슨 일이야
There is news from Luoyang City
뤄양시에서 소식이 왔습니다
Lin Er Wang Li Jun
린 얼 왕 리 준
With Li Lai, King of Xiji
서지왕 리라이와 함께
The king of Liang was enthroned in the capital.
양왕(梁王)이 수도에 즉위하였다.
What
무엇
two idiots
바보 두 명
They are indeed a little impatient
그 사람들은 사실 조금 참을성이 없어
peach
복숭아
Before departure
출발 전
I specifically told the captain
내가 선장에게 구체적으로 말했다.
Let her go all the way
그녀를 끝까지 가게 해주세요
All have to leave a mark
모두 흔적을 남겨야 해
Come to Beijing quickly
빨리 북경으로 오세요
Tell her to leave the city immediately
그녀에게 즉시 도시를 떠나라고 전해주세요
I'm only afraid of Sun Jing
난 Sun Jing이 두려울 뿐이야
Will be furious if he finds out
그 사람이 알면 화낼 거야.
If the city is closed and Dasuo
도시가 폐쇄되고 Dasuo가 있는 경우
I'm worried that the captain will be in danger
선장이 위험할까봐 걱정돼요
I'll leave immediately
나는 즉시 떠날 것이다
Ashu
금연 건강 증진 협회
Please contact me immediately
즉시 연락주세요
our army
우리 군대
tell them
그들에게
Break camp immediately and head south
즉시 캠프를 중단하고 남쪽으로 이동
If the captain cannot leave the city
선장이 도시를 떠날 수 없는 경우
I will try my best
난 내 최선을 다할 것입니다
Want to rescue her too
그 사람도 구하고 싶다
yes
예
let me go
날 보내줘
Why should you arrest me?
왜 나를 체포해야 합니까?
open
열려 있는
let me go
날 보내줘
Why should you arrest me?
왜 나를 체포해야 합니까?
you let go
당신은 놓아
I'm a good person
나는 좋은 사람이다
Why are you arresting me?
왜 나를 체포하는 거죠?
I didn’t expect that your two brothers
네 두 형제가 그럴 줄은 몰랐어
so impatient
너무 참을성이 없어
Incompetent bungler
무능한 서투른 사람
Miss Seventeen Lang Gu is here
미스세븐틴 랑구가 왔어요
Please sit down
앉으세요
Came here late at night in disguise
늦은 밤 변장하고 여기 왔어
what happened
무슨 일이에요
Near Youshi
유시 근처
Someone suddenly came to the palace
누군가 갑자기 궁전에 찾아왔습니다.
Talk about the edict of the Grand Governor
총독의 칙령에 대해 이야기해 보세요.
Want my father to enter the palace
아버지가 궁에 들어가길 바라요
Although my father is reluctant
아버지가 반대하시지만
But I'm afraid of hurting my family
하지만 가족에게 상처를 줄까봐 두렵습니다.
Had to be taken in
입원해야 했어요
at night
밤에
I'll pretend to be a servant
하인인 척 할게요
sneak out
몰래 빠져나가다
Report to you
당신에게 보고하세요
Thank you for your hard work, Miss Gu.
구 선생님, 수고해 주셔서 감사합니다.
I don’t know how safe Mr. Gu is now.
구씨가 지금 얼마나 안전한지 모르겠습니다.
I do not know either
나도 모른다
But I think back then
그런데 그때 생각해보니
Sun Jing did not kill my father
손징은 아버지를 죽이지 않았다
Presumably now
아마도 지금은
I won't take action immediately
당장 조치를 취하지 않겠습니다
yes
예
Prime Minister Gu has a very high reputation
구 총리의 평판이 매우 높다
Sun Jing will not kill him easily
Sun Jing은 그를 쉽게 죽이지 않을 것입니다
Miss Gu
미스구
Don't worry too much
너무 걱정하지 마세요
You guys leave quickly
너희들은 빨리 떠나라
I'm on my way here
난 여기로 가는 중이야
I saw a lot of soldiers and horses searching and arresting them.
나는 많은 군인과 말이 그들을 수색하고 체포하는 것을 보았습니다.
if
만약에
If the emperor's grandson is discovered
황제의 손자가 발견되면
That's bad
그 나쁜
Our Gu family has farmland
우리 구씨네에는 농지가 있어요
If the emperor and his grandson need it,
황제와 그의 손자가 필요하다면,
You can go and avoid it first
먼저 가서 피하면 돼
Do not worry
걱정 하지마
We have our own arrangements
우리만의 준비가 있어요
But Miss Gu
그런데 구씨
Don’t venture out again these days.
요즘에는 다시는 모험을 하지 마세요.
ear
귀
Send Miss Gu back
구씨를 돌려보내세요
yes
예
Miss Gu please
구씨 부탁해요
Search every house for me and don’t let me go.
나를 찾아 집집마다 수색하고 가만 두지 마십시오.
Take it out and let me see
꺼내서 좀 보자
gone
다 쓴
And don’t leave
그리고 떠나지 마세요
You go
너가
stop
멈추다
It's all yours
다 네 것
What are you pretending to be?
당신은 무엇인 척하고 있습니까?
In clothes
옷을 입고
The search started so early in the morning
이른 아침부터 수색이 시작됐어요
I don’t know about Xie Changer and Lao Bao either.
Xie Changer와 Lao Bao에 대해서도 잘 모릅니다.
Can you get away?
도망갈 수 있나요?
sure
확신하는
Moreover
게다가
They also have peaches to support them
그들은 또한 그들을 지원하는 복숭아를 가지고 있습니다
Come over in a moment
잠시만 와봐
meet us
우리와 만나
I want to see something
뭔가 보고 싶어
On this girl
이 소녀에
Something suspicious
의심스러운 것
little lady
작은 아가씨
official
공식적인
How dare you take off your grandfather's clothes
감히 할아버지 옷을 벗기다니
See if my big beard doesn't prick you to death
내 큰 수염이 당신을 찔러 죽지는 않는지 확인해보세요
Don't let go from house to house
이 집 저 집으로 다니지 말라
yes
예
Take a look here
여기를 보세요
there
거기
Go in here and take a look
여기 들어가서 구경해보세요
right
오른쪽
Okay, go over there
알았어, 거기로 가봐
No
아니요
there
거기
Let you take a look today
오늘 좀 봐주세요
Grandpa, I'm awesome
할아버지, 저 정말 대단해요
Brother Bao gets out of the way
바오 형제가 비켜갑니다
Get out of the way
비켜가세요
Brother Bao
바오 형제
You deserve it
당신은 그럴 자격이 있어요
Hurry up, hurry up
서둘러, 서둘러
Come and take a look inside
와서 내부를 살펴보세요
hurry up
서둘러요
Search carefully
신중하게 검색하세요
You two go over there
너희 둘은 저쪽으로 가라
yes
예
Go upstairs and have a look
위로 올라가서 좀 보세요
Walk
걷다
benefactor
후원자
hurry up
서둘러요
It turned out to be benefactor
은인으로 밝혀졌습니다
benefactor
후원자
empress
황후
Got the news
소식을 받았어요
After King Liang ascended the throne,
양왕(梁王)이 왕위에 오른 후,
The governor was furious
주지사는 분노했다
Not only intensified investigations in Beijing and China,
베이징과 중국에서 강화된 조사뿐만 아니라,
He also recruited many old ministers
그는 또한 많은 노장관을 영입했습니다.
They are not allowed to leave the palace
그들은 궁전을 떠날 수 없습니다
Afraid of colluding with Liang Wang
Liang Wang과 공모할까 두려워
The person sent to deliver a message to General Han
한장군에게 전갈을 전하기 위해 파견된 사람
are you back
당신은 돌아왔나요?
Returned from summons
소환에서 돌아왔다
say temporarily
일시적으로 말하다
No news about General Han yet
아직 한 장군에 대한 소식은 없습니다
but
하지만
Seeing General Han
한 장군을 만나다
bodyguard
친위대
Presumably General Han
아마도 한 장군
I have escaped temporarily with my grandson.
손자와 함께 임시 탈출했습니다.
No audio is a good thing
오디오가 없는 것은 좋은 일입니다.
We can't find them
우리는 그들을 찾을 수 없습니다
Naturally, no one else can find them.
당연히 다른 누구도 찾을 수 없습니다.
empress
황후
Now people in Beijing are panicked
지금 베이징 시민들은 당황하고 있다.
Li Yi led the Western Army to enter Aoguan
리이(Li Yi)는 서군을 이끌고 아오관(Aoguan)에 입성했습니다.
Presumably at any time
아마도 언제든지
Metropolitan soldiers besieged West Changjing
수도권군이 서창징을 포위함
Now we are ordering the people in Beijing to
이제 우리는 베이징 사람들에게 다음과 같이 명령하고 있습니다.
Step up to stock up on food
음식을 비축하려면 한 단계 더 나아가세요.
Sun Jing has urgently sent a secret order
Sun Jing은 긴급하게 비밀 명령을 보냈습니다.
Recall the Hundreds of Vietnamese Army
수백명의 베트남군을 기억하라
If the army returns,
군대가 돌아오면
Easy to defend but difficult to attack
방어는 쉽지만 공격은 어렵다
Li Yi may not be able to win.
리이는 이길 수 없을지도 모른다.
Then we want
그러면 우리는 원한다
it's not urgent
급한 건 아니야
urgent matter
긴급한 문제
We need to find General Han first
먼저 한장군을 찾아야 해
Make sure your grandson is safe
손자가 안전한지 확인하세요
Find a way to send a message to Li Yi
Li Yi에게 메시지를 보낼 방법을 찾아보세요
I have something important
나한테 중요한 게 있어
discuss with him
그와 토론하다
If not today
오늘이 아니면
General Han sacrificed his life to save me
한 장군은 나를 구하기 위해 목숨을 바쳤다
I died again
나는 또 죽었다
Your Majesty, you don't have to be like this
폐하, 이럴 필요는 없습니다
This is my duty
이것이 나의 의무이다
Sun Jing's secret cavalry
손징의 비밀 기병대
The pursuit is so tight
추적이 너무 빡빡해서
Maybe it was King Qin’s military victory.
아마도 진왕의 군사적 승리였을 것이다.
Thief Sun's last desperate struggle
도둑 태양의 마지막 처절한 사투
Just crazy
그냥 미쳤어
I've been running away in embarrassment these days
요즘 부끄러워서 도망가고 있어요
always in danger
항상 위험에 처해 있다
I don’t know Brother Seventeen
세븐틴 형님은 모르겠어요
After the restoration of the capital
수도 복원 후
Are there any troops approaching West Changjing?
서창징에 접근하는 군대가 있습니까?
Wait until we get rid of it
우리가 그것을 제거할 때까지 기다리세요
The chasing cavalry behind
뒤에서 추격하는 기병대
Then you can know the news from outside
그럼 외부 소식을 알 수 있겠네요
Several benefactors
여러 후원자
I just borrowed it to buy fruit
방금 과일 사려고 빌렸어요
I went to the street to inquire about it.
나는 그것에 대해 알아보기 위해 거리로 나갔다.
every shop
모든 가게
Together with the Yiguan Inn
이관여관과 함께
Everyone is searching for any strangers
모두들 낯선 사람을 찾고 있어요
Even if there is a government guide
정부 지침이 있어도
They will also be scrutinized carefully.
또한 면밀히 조사될 것입니다.
Several benefactors
여러 후원자
First at the old woman's place
먼저 할머니 집에서
Live in peace for a few days
며칠간 평안하게 지내세요
If any neighbor knows
혹시 아는 이웃이 있다면
old woman
늙은 여자
I have some words to cover it up
가릴 말이 좀 있는데
if we continue
우리가 계속한다면
Stay here with Aunt Yang
여기서 양이모와 함께 지내요
I'm just afraid that it will end up hurting them in the end.
결국 그 사람들에게 상처를 줄까 두렵습니다.
Better wait until dark
어두워질 때까지 기다리는 것이 좋습니다
Let's sneak out over the wall quietly
조용히 벽 너머로 몰래 빠져나가자
Taozi sent a reply
Taozi가 답장을 보냈습니다
Said the interrogation was very strict
심문이 매우 엄격하다고 하더군요
But luckily we have found the captain
하지만 다행히 우리는 선장을 찾았습니다
Where you are currently staying
현재 머물고 있는 곳
It’s safe for now
지금은 안전해요
It’s just that the city is going street by street
도시가 거리에서 거리로 나아가고 있다는 것뿐입니다.
Let Li Zheng conduct an inventory from house to house.
Li Zheng이 집집을 방문하여 목록을 작성하게 하세요.
Just worry about how long it takes
시간이 얼마나 걸릴지 걱정만 하세요
Exposing one's hidden possessions
숨겨진 물건을 폭로하다
But the captain is clever
하지만 선장은 똑똑하다
I must be able to think of a way
내가 방법을 생각해낼 수 있어야 해
Escaped from the city
도시에서 탈출
Hidden piles in the city
도시의 숨겨진 더미
is it possible
가능합니까?
Contact people in the palace
궁궐에 있는 사람들에게 연락하다
Well enough
그럼 충분해
Then wait a moment
그럼 잠시만 기다려주세요
Waiting for the captain to leave the city
선장이 도시를 떠나기를 기다리고 있다
yes
예
our army
우리 군대
How are you preparing?
어떻게 준비하고 있나요?
We will arrive at Aoguan soon.
우리는 곧 아오관(Aoguan)에 도착할 것입니다.
good
좋은
I will go visit Pei Yuan first
먼저 페이위안을 만나러 갈게요
Talking about the emperor's grandson and the school captain now
지금 황제의 손자와 교장에 대한 이야기
in danger
위험에
Our Cui family army
우리 추이 가문의 군대
You can go to support
지원하러 가셔도 됩니다
We need to ask General Pei first
먼저 페이 장군에게 물어봐야 해요
Put our army into Aoguan
우리 군대를 오관에 투입하다
You go and deliver the message
네가 가서 메시지를 전해라.
Tell them to be prepared
준비하라고 하세요.
yes
예
I thought of a way
나는 방법을 생각했다
Even if we reveal what we are hiding
우리가 숨기고 있는 것을 드러낸다 해도
It won’t hurt Aunt Yang either.
양 이모도 다치지 않을 거예요.
What method
어떤 방법
Aunt Yang’s daughter Yang Qiniang
양 이모의 딸 양치앙(Yang Qiniang)
With a man named Xu Sanlang
Xu Sanlang이라는 남자와 함께
Engaged
약혼한
But I asked Yang Qiniang
그런데 나는 양치앙에게 물었습니다.
Neighbors
이웃
I have never seen this Xu Sanlang
나는 이것을 본 적이 없다 Xu Sanlang
Qiniang
치앙
You came back from outside the city that day
그 날 당신은 도시 밖에서 돌아왔죠
Did you go to a relative or friend's house in the countryside?
시골에 있는 친척이나 친구 집에 가보셨나요?
If the time comes
때가 되면
If we have a chance to escape
우리에게 탈출할 기회가 생긴다면
I'm afraid you
나는 너가 두려워
I still have to go to relatives and friends’ houses again
나는 아직도 친척과 친구 집에 다시 가야만 한다.
Just avoid it
그냥 피하세요
So that the neighbors will not be suspicious
이웃들이 의심하지 않도록
Went that day
그날 갔다
Not from outside
외부에서가 아닌
It’s my fiancé’s home
내 약혼자의 집이에요
His name is Xu Sanlang
그의 이름은 Xu Sanlang입니다.
Make an appointment with me
나랑 약속을 잡아
But unfortunately
하지만 불행하게도
He went out to sell cloth
그는 옷을 팔러 나갔다.
Otherwise that day
그렇지 않으면 그날
You can't let me and my mother-in-law
나와 내 시어머니를 놔둘 수는 없습니다
Go out of town to get food
도시 밖으로 나가서 음식을 사오세요
in danger
위험에
I see
알겠어요
Yang Qiniang told me
양치앙이 나에게 말했다.
Her mother-in-law had already given it to her
시어머니는 이미 그것을 그녀에게 주셨습니다.
The wedding dress and dowry are ready
웨딩드레스와 지참금이 준비되었습니다
Just waiting for Xu Sanlang to come and marry him
Xu Sanlang이 와서 그와 결혼하기를 기다리고 있습니다.
Yang Qiniang and I are similar in age
양치앙과 나는 나이가 비슷하다.
The figure is almost the same
수치는 거의 비슷해요
Wait until the time
그 시간까지 기다리세요
You pretend to be Xu Sanlang
당신은 Xu Sanlang인 척합니다
Welcoming bride at door
문앞에서 환영받는 신부
I'll put on my wedding clothes
나는 결혼식 옷을 입을 것이다
Cover with HiPa
HiPa로 덮다
Until then
그때까지
Everyone will only think
다들 생각만 하겠지만
I am Yang Qiniang
나는 양치앙이다
Sitting in a sedan chair
세단 의자에 앉아
Walking out of the city in a hurry
서둘러 시내를 빠져나오다
Also upright
또한 똑바로
Marriage documents as guarantee
보증으로서의 결혼 서류
There won’t be any difficulties at the city gate.
성문에서는 어려움이 없을 것입니다.
no
아니요
If you do this
이렇게 하면
Not only did Aunt Yang take risks,
양이모는 위험을 감수했을 뿐만 아니라
It will still be delayed
아직은 미뤄지겠죠
Miss Yang’s life events
Miss Yang의 인생 사건
My benefactor saved me
나의 은인이 나를 구해주었다
The lives of the old woman and the little girl
노부인과 어린 소녀의 삶
Why did you say this?
왜 이런 말을 했나요?
This is a clever plan
이건 영리한 계획이네
But it is
하지만 그것은
Marrying someone in the name of my little girl
내 어린 딸의 이름으로 누군가와 결혼하다
What about taking risks?
위험을 감수하는 것은 어떻습니까?
Wait until Saburo comes back
사부로가 돌아올 때까지 기다리세요
I quietly sent my little girl there
나는 조용히 내 딸을 그곳으로 보냈다.
Just pay him a visit
그냥 그 사람을 방문해보세요
returning a Favour many times more
몇 번이나 부탁을 갚는다
not to mention
언급 할 필요없는
My benefactor once saved our lives
나의 후원자는 한때 우리의 생명을 구했습니다
Only the benefactor escapes danger
은인만이 위험을 피한다
Only then can the old woman have peace of mind.
그래야만 노파는 마음의 평화를 얻을 수 있다.
Yang A
양아
Thank you Auntie for your help
도와주신 이모님께 감사드립니다
Jushichiro
주시치로
Let's get out of the city quickly
빨리 도시를 벗어나자
That's the best policy
그게 최선의 정책이다
in this way
이런 식으로
Thank you Aunt Yang
양이모님 감사합니다
stop stop stop
그만 그만 그만
It's so festive
너무 축제같아
This military man
이 군인놈아
Marry a wife today
오늘 아내와 결혼하세요
This is the marriage document issued by Satomasa
사토마사가 발행한 혼인증명서입니다.
Xu Sanlang from Xujiazhuang outside the city
도시 외곽 쉬자좡(Xujiazhuang) 출신의 쉬산랑(Xu Sanlang)
Want to marry Qiniang of the Yang family
양씨 치앙과 결혼하고 싶다
yes
예
Marry Yang Qiniang today
오늘 양 치앙과 결혼하세요
This is the wedding cake from the He family on East Street
이것은 East Street에 있는 He 가문의 웨딩 케이크입니다.
Provide food for the military master
군장에게 음식을 제공하다
Everyone says He’s cakes are delicious
다들 그 사람 케이크 맛있다고 하던데
Then I won't delay
그럼 지체하지 않을게
It's time for you
당신을 위한 시간이에요
Let's go
갑시다
Thank you, Junye
고마워요, 준예
Walk
걷다
Emperor Sun this time
이번에는 썬 황제
Even though I took someone else’s clothes
남의 옷을 빼앗았는데도
But put on the happy outfit just now
하지만 지금 당장 행복한 옷을 입으세요
Put it in someone's yard
다른 사람의 마당에 놓아두세요
This can be described as bartering
이는 물물교환이라고 할 수 있다
Compared with the previous self-pickup service
기존 셀프픽업 서비스와 비교
Still made a lot of progress
그래도 많이 발전했네
Didn't this happen suddenly before?
예전에 갑자기 이런 일이 있지 않았나요?
actually
실제로
I quite like it
나는 그것을 꽤 좋아한다
Wearing this wedding dress
이 웨딩드레스를 입고
school lieutenant
학교 중위
peach
복숭아
The young master just sent a message to say
젊은 마스터가 방금 메시지를 보냈습니다.
A team of our Cui Jiajun
Cui Jiajun 팀
They were dispersed by Sun Jing's people.
그들은 Sun Jing의 사람들에 의해 흩어졌습니다.
so he hopes
그래서 그는 희망한다
Let's go as soon as possible
최대한 빨리 가자
Let’s go back to Aoguan together
함께 아오관으로 돌아가자
That being the case
그렇긴 한데
Then let's change our route and meet up.
그럼 경로를 바꿔서 만나자.
Is Huangsun going back to Aoguan?
Huangsun은 Aoguan으로 돌아가나요?
Although only a hundred miles
비록 100마일밖에 안 됐지만
But the terrain here is complicated
하지만 이곳의 지형은 복잡해요
I'd better go with you
너랑 같이 가는 게 좋을 것 같아
in this case
이 경우
Emperor Sun is worried
쑨제이는 걱정한다
I'll join the army
나는 군대에 갈 것이다
It will be detrimental to Aoguan
Aoguan에 해로울 것입니다
Of course
물론
You are full of tricks
넌 트릭이 가득해
I have to keep an eye on you personally
개인적으로 당신을 감시해야 해요
Walk
걷다
Young Master
젊은 스승
Taozi sent back a message
Taozi가 메시지를 다시 보냈습니다.
The captain has left the city
선장은 도시를 떠났다
Where is Li Yi?
리 이(Li Yi)는 어디에 있나요?
I'm still with the captain right now
난 지금 여전히 선장과 함께 있어요
We will be able to return to Aoguan in a few days.
우리는 며칠 안에 Aoguan으로 돌아갈 수 있을 것입니다.
How is our army settled?
우리 군대는 어떻게 정착됐나요?
Already settled in Aoguan
이미 Aoguan에 정착했습니다.
Come and take a look at what I wrote
와서 내가 쓴 글 좀 봐봐
Punish him and avoid future troubles
그를 처벌하고 미래의 문제를 피하십시오
These words are full of energy
이 말엔 에너지가 넘친다
Rich writing style
풍부한 글쓰기 스타일
It seems that the young master has recovered
젊은 주인이 회복된 것 같습니다
The injury naturally healed
부상은 자연스럽게 치유됐다.
That being the case
그렇긴 한데
You should take away past mistakes
과거의 실수를 없애야 해
as a lesson
교훈으로
To avoid future troubles
앞으로의 문제를 방지하기 위해
Cui Lin sent someone to deliver the letter
추이린은 편지를 전달하기 위해 사람을 보냈습니다
Said he could cooperate with me inside and outside
그는 내외부에서 나와 협력할 수 있다고 하더군요
Recover Aoguan
아오관을 회복하라
In exchange for my retreat to Yingzhou
내가 잉저우로 퇴각하는 대가로
Cui Linnai is Cui Yi’s only son
Cui Linnai는 Cui Yi의 외아들입니다.
Cui Yi left Yingzhou
Cui Yi는 Yingzhou를 떠났습니다.
Clearly ambitious
분명히 야심찬
Intent on the world
세상에 대한 의도
Now Cui Lin is not doing her job well
이제 Cui Lin은 일을 잘하지 못합니다.
Recuperating in Aoguan
아오관(Aoguan)에서 요양 중
Send this letter
이 편지를 보내세요
It makes some sense
말이 되네요
The so-called three heroes of the country at that time
당시 우리나라의 소위 3대 영웅
Except for Pei Xian, who is also called me
나라고도 불리는 Pei Xian을 제외하고
It’s just Cui Yi
바로 최이(Cui Yi)입니다
Old man Cui Yi
추이 노인
Since my wife died
아내가 죽은 이후로
Fighting like crazy all day long
하루종일 미친듯이 싸워
This is the current situation
이것이 현재 상황이다
He is natural
그는 자연스럽다
I won't miss this opportunity either
나 역시 이 기회를 놓치지 않을 것이다.
but
하지만
Even if he cares about the world
그 사람이 세상을 걱정하더라도
Look at him too
그 사람도 좀 봐
Do you have this ability?
당신에게 이런 능력이 있나요?
Cuijiaying Prefecture was besieged
추자잉현이 포위당했다
His son Cui Lin
그의 아들 추이린
Can't you sit still?
가만히 앉아 있을 수는 없나요?
Grand Governor
총독
Although Cui Lin said it with certainty,
최린이 자신있게 말했지만,
But he clearly
하지만 그는 분명히
He had many contacts with the Zhenxi Army
그는 Zhenxi 군대와 많은 접촉을 가졌습니다.
The Governor still needs to be careful
주지사는 여전히 조심해야합니다
There is fraud in this
여기에는 사기가 있습니다.
This guy
이 남자
What tricks do you want to play in front of me?
내 앞에서 무슨 장난을 치고 싶니?
Still tender
아직 부드러워
Reply to Cui Lin
답장하다 추이린
tell him
그에게 말해
You can send someone to work with him inside and outside.
당신은 내부와 외부에서 그와 함께 일할 사람을 보낼 수 있습니다.
but
하지만
Have to wait until Auguan
아우구안까지 기다려야 함
After falling into my hands
내 손에 빠진 후
I will withdraw
철회하겠습니다
The army sent to Yingzhou
군대가 영주(應州)에 파견됨
yes
예
Your Highness
전하
General Han
한 장군
Are you still getting used to living here?
아직도 이곳 생활에 익숙해지고 있나요?
Huayang Town is very clean
화양 타운은 매우 깨끗합니다
only
오직
It's not far from Xichangjing
시창징에서 멀지 않아요
we live here
우리는 여기에 산다
Is there really no danger?
정말 위험은 없나요?
I'm afraid no one can think of it
아무도 그것을 생각하지 못할까봐 두려워요
We will choose the distance from West Changjing
West Changjing에서의 거리를 선택하겠습니다
Settling down in such a close town
이렇게 가까운 동네에 정착하다니
The so-called darkness under the lamp
등불 아래 소위 어둠
But that's it
하지만 그게 다야
What's more, Sun Jing
게다가 쑨징
Recently, I have been trapped by the Zhenxi Army.
최근 저는 진시군에게 갇혔습니다.
It's the moment of great distress
엄청난 고민의 순간이다
We can
우리는 할 수 있다
Stay peacefully for a while
한동안 평안하게 지내세요
General Han
한 장군
Your Highness, please speak directly if you have something to say.
전하, 하실 말씀이 있으시면 직접 말씀해 주십시오.
After Liang Wangshu ascended the throne,
양왕숙이 왕위에 오른 후
Sun Jing will still try his best
Sun Jing은 여전히 ​​최선을 다할 것입니다
Hunt us?
우리를 사냥한다고?
I'm afraid it will be worse than before
예전보다 더 심해질까봐
Although King Liang ascended the throne,
양왕이 즉위했지만,
But the world is orthodox
하지만 세상은 정통이다
In fact, it is you, Your Highness
사실은 바로 당신입니다, 전하
you are
당신은
The only bloodline of the late prince
고(故) 왕자의 유일한 혈통
Thief Sun also knows very well
Thief Sun도 잘 알고 있습니다.
If I could capture you alive, His Highness
만약 당신을 생포할 수 있다면 전하
I can hold His Highness hostage
전하를 인질로 잡을 수 있어요
To order the world
세상을 주문하려면
Uncle Liang
리앙 삼촌
I don't quite remember
잘 기억이 나지 않는다
what does he look like
그는 어떻게 생겼 니
He didn't come to the palace often before.
그는 이전에 궁전에 자주 오지 않았습니다.
In fact, King Liang was not worried
사실 양왕은 걱정하지 않았다.
Only Li Yi, the son of King Liang,
오직 양왕의 아들 이이만이
Now Liang Wang ascends the throne
이제 양왕(梁王)이 왕위에 오릅니다.
Just afraid
그냥 두려워
Can Brother Seventeen know it?
세븐틴 형제는 그것을 알 수 있을까요?
Your Highness
전하
Don't trust people's hearts gullibly
사람의 마음을 함부로 믿지 마세요
Give
주다
Where did the nuts come from?
견과류는 어디서 왔나요?
The captain gave him a nickname
선장은 그에게 별명을 지어주었다.
called dried fruit
말린 과일이라고 불리는
dried fruit
말린 과일
I heard this is not a good buy.
나는 이것이 좋은 구매가 아니라고 들었습니다.
I tried it and it was really delicious
먹어봤는데 진짜 맛있더라구요
Captain knows I like it
캡틴은 내가 좋아하는 걸 알아
Just bring me some more
좀 더 가져다 주세요
Thank you so much for this peach sister.
이 복숭아 자매에게 정말 감사합니다.
I asked for this
나는 이것을 요청했다
Enough, enough, enough
충분해, 충분해, 충분해
Thanks to my ears
내 귀 덕분에
to eat
먹다
Such crispy and delicious dried fruits
바삭바삭하고 맛있는 말린 과일들
This dried fruit
이 말린 과일
It's really delicious
정말 맛있어요
What does it mean to be blessed by me?
나에게 축복을 받는다는 것은 무엇을 의미합니까?
Peach is not for each of us
복숭아는 우리 각자를위한 것이 아닙니다
Are they all good?
모두 좋은가요?
Didn't you notice?
눈치채지 못하셨나요?
Sister Peach
피치 자매
Very good to you
당신에게 아주 좋은
no
아니요
Taozi is a very nice person
타오즈는 정말 좋은 사람이에요
Why did she leave?
그녀는 왜 떠났나요?
I asked you, are you stupid?
내가 물었잖아, 너 바보야?
Why don't you hurry up and chase her?
서둘러서 그녀를 쫓아가는 게 어때요?
Hurry why?
서둘러 왜?
If you don't go after me,
나를 따라가지 않으면,
Sister Taozi will poison you
Taozi 자매가 당신을 독살 할 것입니다
Hurry up
서둘러요
Go, go, go
가, 가, 가
peach
복숭아
this time
이 시간
Couldn't think of a way to break the city
도시를 무너뜨릴 방법을 생각할 수 없었어요
On the contrary, it is a warning
오히려 경고다.
It seems we have to make plans again
다시 계획을 세워야 할 것 같아
Let’s see how to regain West Changjing in the future
앞으로 서창징을 어떻게 되찾을지 지켜보자
Wait until the future to recapture West Changjing
미래가 서창징을 탈환할 때까지 기다리세요
what's your plan
당신의 계획은 무엇입니까
Until then
그때까지
There will definitely be no more war.
더 이상 전쟁은 없을 것입니다.
I will welcome my grandson back to the court
나는 내 손자가 법정으로 돌아온 것을 환영할 것이다
persuade my father
아버지를 설득하다
Make grandson the crown prince
손자를 왕세자로 만들다
Then I'll go back to Laolan Pass
그럼 다시 라오란 고개로 돌아가겠습니다
And you
당신은요
Go back to Yingzhou?
영저우로 돌아가나요?
Prince Liang has already ascended the throne as emperor.
양왕은 이미 황제로 즉위했습니다.
You are the emperor's son
당신은 황제의 아들입니다
Not staying in Beijing
베이징에 머물지 않고
Do you really want to go back to Laolan Pass?
정말로 라오란 고개로 돌아가고 싶나요?
I like Laolanguan
나는 라오랑관을 좋아한다
Don’t like Xichangjing
Xichangjing을 좋아하지 않는다
otherwise
그렇지 않으면
I was
나는 ~였다
You won't find a reason to make a mistake
실수할 이유를 찾지 못할 것이다
The late Emperor asked me to be demoted to Laolan Pass.
고(故) 황제께서 나에게 라오란관(Laolan Pass)으로 강등시켜 달라고 요청하셨다.
At that time you were the son of King Liang
그 당시 당신은 양왕의 아들이었습니다.
Among the dozen or so royal grandsons
십여 명 정도의 왕족 손자들 가운데
The most inconspicuous one
가장 눈에 띄지 않는 것
Nature will come and go freely
자연은 자유롭게 왔다 갔다 할 것이다
It’s no different now
지금도 다르지 않아요
Father likes my brothers
아버지는 내 형제들을 좋아하신다.
Let them stay with their father
그들이 아버지와 함께 있게 해주세요
And you
당신은요
You still have not answered my question
당신은 아직 내 질문에 대답하지 않았습니다
Will you return to Yingzhou?
잉저우로 돌아갈 건가요?
how
어떻게
The emperor and grandson are afraid of my Cui family army
황제와 손자는 내 추이 가문의 군대를 두려워합니다
Will be the same as Sun Jing
쑨원이랑 똑같을거야
Aiming at West Changjing
서창징을 목표로
I don’t want to go back to Yingzhou anymore
더 이상 영주로 돌아가고 싶지 않아요
When I left Yingzhou
영주를 떠날 때
Have such a wish
그런 소원을 가지세요
I hope the war can be calmed down
전쟁이 진정되길 바랍니다
Peace in the world
세계의 평화
Let the people
사람들을 보자
Everyone can live a good and stable life
누구나 착하고 안정적인 삶을 살 수 있다
If one day in the future
만약 미래의 어느 날
We can really take back West Changjing
우리는 정말로 West Changjing을 되찾을 수 있습니다
That must mean the world is at peace
그건 세상이 평화롭다는 뜻이겠지
Why still
왜 아직도
Will there be war and strife again?
다시 전쟁과 분쟁이 일어날 것인가?
Yes Yes Yes
예 예 예
I have a villainous heart
나는 악랄한 마음을 가지고 있다
I hope Mr. Xiaowei will have a lot of
Xiaowei 씨가 많은 것을 갖기를 바랍니다.
Don't be offended
화내지 마세요
After that day of peace
그날의 평화가 지나면
what do you most want to do
가장 하고 싶은 게 뭐야?
its me
나야
I haven't thought about it yet
아직 생각해본 적은 없어요
The world is so vast
세상은 참 넓다
I have never been to Laolan Pass
나는 Laolan Pass에 가본 적이 없습니다.
There are many places
많은 곳이 있어요
I've never seen it
나는 그것을 본 적이 없다
so
그래서
I want to see them all
다 보고 싶어요
You want to travel around the world
세계여행을 하고 싶으신가요?
Then will you come to Laolan Pass?
그럼 라오란 고개로 오실래요?
one day
어느 날
I will go to Laolan Pass
라오란 고개로 가겠습니다
Go and have a look
가서 좀 봐
The desert wind and smoke you mentioned
네가 말한 사막의 바람과 연기
And the Laolan River
그리고 라오란 강
good
좋은
It’s a deal
그것은 거래의
Let you talk nonsense
말도 안되는 소리를 하게 놔두세요
Who treats you well
누가 당신을 잘 대해주나요?
peach girl
복숭아 소녀
Don't come here
여기 오지 마세요
What happened to you
당신에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
What did you say happened to me?
나한테 무슨 일이 일어났다고 했어?
I made you angry again
내가 또 널 화나게 했어
but I do not know
하지만 나는 몰라
why make you angry
왜 화나게 만들어?
have no idea
전혀 모른다
I don’t know, just think about it
모르겠어, 그냥 생각해봐
Yes or no
예 혹은 아니오
Because I said something wrong
내가 뭔가 잘못 말했으니까
sorry
죄송합니다
me
나
Just not very good at talking
그냥 말을 잘 못해요
Then tell me
그럼 말 해주세요
What did you say wrong?
무슨 말을 잘못했어요?
me
나
elm head
느릅나무 머리
Get away from me
나에게서 도망
peach
복숭아
Out of the way
방법 중
empress
황후
There is news from General Han
한 장군의 소식이 있습니다
Said he was a grandson
손자라고 하더군요
Temporarily settled down
임시로 정착했어요
Very good
매우 좋은
It’s really blessed by gods and Buddhas
정말 신과 부처님의 축복을 받았습니다.
Congratulations to the empress
황후님 축하드립니다
I can feel at ease for now
지금은 마음이 편할 것 같아요
A few days ago, the Governor
며칠 전 도지사님이
Deliberately concealing the deployment of troops and horses
군대와 말의 배치를 의도적으로 은폐하는 행위
I always feel like something will happen
항상 무슨 일이 일어날 것 같은 느낌이 들어요
It was the Grand Governor who discovered where Taisun was.
태순이 있는 곳을 발견한 사람은 태수였습니다.
If it's to capture a child
아이를 붙잡기 위해서라면
Will so many troops be dispatched?
그렇게 많은 병력이 파견될 것인가?
That was aimed at Luoyang, the capital of Gu.
그것은 고나라의 수도인 낙양(洛陽)을 겨냥한 것이었다.
Or reinforce Yingzhou?
아니면 잉저우를 강화할 것인가?
I don't know either
나도 모르겠어요
The person sent to deliver a message to Li Yi
리이에게 메시지를 전달하기 위해 파견된 사람
Is there any news coming back?
돌아온다는 소식이 있나요?
He said he hasn’t seen Li Yi yet
아직 리이를 본 적이 없다고 하더군요
So there is no news for now
그래서 지금은 소식이 없어요
I only hope for the Governor
주지사님만 바랄게요
Not going to Aoguan
아오관에는 안 가
Maybe
아마도
Maybe I think too much
어쩌면 내 생각이 너무 많은 걸지도 몰라
what are you thinking about
당신은 무엇에 대한 생각
I remember my first expedition
첫 번째 탐험을 기억합니다.
Exit from Fuyuan Gate to West Changjing
Fuyuan Gate에서 West Changjing 방향으로 나가세요.
that time
그때
I'm still one
난 아직 하나야
The little-known Guedesgo
잘 알려지지 않은 게데스고
several years passed
몇 년이 지났다
Accumulation of military exploits
군사적 공적 축적
Only then was he promoted to the middle rank of Huaihua
그제서야 그는 화이화(淮淮)의 중위로 승진했다.
Follow your boss to Beijing to resume your duties
업무를 재개하려면 상사를 따라 베이징으로 가세요.
I just feel that Beijing is prosperous
베이징이 번영하고 있는 것 같아요
Compared with the wind and sand on the battlefield
전장의 바람과 모래에 비하면
It's like a world away
마치 세상이 먼 것 같아요
Why do you suddenly remember to say this?
왜 갑자기 이런 말이 생각나지?
look
바라보다
The sun is going to set
해가 진다
The sun shines on
태양이 빛난다
On the glazed tiles of the palace
궁전의 유리 타일 위에
Follow the yellow sand in the northwest
북서쪽의 황사를 따라가세요
They are all as red as blood
다들 피처럼 붉어
A Jing
아징
fine
괜찮은
I just suddenly remembered the past
갑자기 옛날 생각이 나네요
that day
그 날
Outside Ilolu
외부 합병증
I lead an army of 100,000
나는 10만의 군대를 이끈다
In the setting sun like blood
피처럼 지는 해에
Waiting for the horn of charge
충전의 뿔을 기다리며
Although there are thousands of troops
수천명의 병력이 있음에도 불구하고
But the surrounding areas are vast
하지만 주변 지역은 넓습니다.
It's as quiet as today
오늘처럼 조용하네요
I'm not afraid of anything
난 아무것도 두렵지 않아
As long as I can be with you
내가 당신과 함께 있을 수 있는 한
That boy Li Yi
그 소년 리이
Thought they occupied Aoguan
그들이 Aoguan을 점령했다고 생각함
Can we force Xichangjing?
Xichangjing을 강요할 수 있나요?
A Jing
아징
I don't want to hear these things anymore
더 이상 이런 말을 듣고 싶지 않아요
Waiting for peace in the world
세계의 평화를 기다리며
You and I can go to Lishan
너와 나는 리산으로 갈 수 있어
Stay longer
더 오래 머물다
good
좋은
Must go
꼭 가야 해
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
What happened
무슨 일이에요
You've been angry for two days
이틀 동안 화났잖아
When hitting the tip
팁을 칠 때
Ignore Xie Changer
Xie 체인저 무시
Who is he?
그는 누구입니까?
When hitting the tip
팁을 칠 때
Why should I pay attention to him?
내가 왜 그 사람에게 관심을 기울여야 합니까?
There is a strange noise in front
앞에서 이상한 소리가 나요
I guess there's an army nearby
근처에 군대가 있는 것 같아
Just don't distinguish between friend and foe
아군과 적군을 구분하지 마세요
Stop for a moment
잠시만 멈춰주세요
school lieutenant
학교 중위
The troops we were scattered by
우리가 흩어진 군대
Just ahead
바로 앞
The third child
세 번째 아이
Just bear with me a little longer
조금만 더 참아주세요
Slower
느리게
General Pei
페이 장군
Why did Sun Jing’s troops
손징의 군대는 왜 그랬을까?
He suddenly rushed out
그 사람 갑자기 급히 나가서
Why Cui Jiajun?
왜 최자준인가?
It is necessary to cooperate inside and outside
안팎의 협력이 필요하다
Attack us
우리를 공격하다
Auguan
아우구안
We work hard
우리는 열심히 일한다
The defeated Aoguan
패배한 아오관
General Pei
페이 장군
Let’s hold down the Western Army
서부군을 제압하자
So many brothers died
너무 많은 형제들이 죽었어
General Pei
페이 장군
how
어떻게
Jushichiro
주시치로
You are so awesome
너 진짜 짱이다
When I entered the camp just now
방금 캠프에 들어왔을 때
You realize something is wrong
뭔가 잘못됐다는 걸 깨닫는다
When you ask me to feed the horse
말에게 먹이를 달라고 하면
pay attention
주의를 기울이다
I looked carefully
유심히 살펴보니
Found their food and baggage
음식과 짐을 찾았어요
No damage
손상 없음
If you go by what Taozi said,
도자가 말한대로 가면,
The Cui family army was dispersed by the army
추이 가문의 군대는 군대에 의해 해산되었습니다
So it's a bit embarrassing
그래서 좀 부담스럽네요
But their military appearance was tidied up
하지만 그들의 군복은 단정했다
It doesn’t look like I’ve encountered a strong enemy recently.
최근에는 강한 적을 만난 것 같지 않습니다.
peach
복숭아
It's the young master who is sending you a message
당신에게 메시지를 보내는 사람은 젊은 스승입니다
It is said that this group of troops was dispersed by the army
이 부대가 군대에 의해 해산되었다고 합니다.
So you asked us to come and meet
그래서 우리한테 와서 만나자고 했어
yes
예
As soon as we arrived
우리가 도착하자마자
Just give me hot water
뜨거운 물만 주세요
let me wash up
나 좀 씻어줘
But now is not the time to cook
하지만 지금은 요리할 때가 아니다.
Why is there a fire?
왜 화재가 발생합니까?
What do you mean, Colonel?
무슨 말이에요, 대령님?
I always feel something is wrong
나는 항상 뭔가 잘못됐다고 느낀다
If they were dispersed by the army
군대에 의해 해산된 경우
Nature will be alert everywhere
자연은 어디에서나 경계할 것입니다
Why not while cooking?
요리하는 동안에는 어떨까요?
There's still a fire going
아직도 불이 계속 나고 있어요
But here it is
하지만 여기 있어요
Our Cui Jiajun’s camp
우리 Cui Jiajun의 캠프
We just met
우리는 방금 만났어
leading general
주요 장군
He also said that he was dispersed by the army.
그는 또한 군대에 의해 해산되었다고 말했습니다.
school lieutenant
학교 중위
What do you think
어떻게 생각하나요
something is wrong
뭔가 잘못되었다
When I entered the camp just now
방금 캠프에 들어왔을 때
discover their horseshoes
그들의 말굽을 발견하다
Badly worn
심하게 마모됨
The soldiers' boots are also full of mud
군인들의 부츠에도 진흙이 가득하다
It's like marching all the way here
마치 여기까지 행진하는 것 같아
if washed away
씻어내면
80%
80%
We still have to wait for the main camp.
아직 메인캠프를 기다려야 합니다.
Or
또는
Send a team over to visit
팀을 보내서 방문하세요
Not in a hurry to march
서두르지 말고 행진하라
That's why I let you feed the horses
그래서 말에게 먹이를 주게 해준 거야
Go and find out
가서 알아보세요
Jushichiro
주시치로
So what should we do now
그럼 이제 우리는 무엇을 해야 할까요?
Aying
아잉
Since you have
당신이 가지고 있기 때문에
Peace is here
평화가 여기에 있다
Then I'll go back to Aoguan first.
그럼 먼저 아오관으로 돌아가겠습니다.
Let's go together
같이 가자
It's not far from Aoguan
아오관에서 멀지 않은 곳에 있어요
Now that everything is together
이제 모든 것이 하나로 합쳐졌으니
Let’s go to Aoguan together
같이 아오관으로 가자
good
좋은
Everybody keep up
모두들 힘내세요
Come on
어서 해봐요
Follow behind
뒤를 따라가다
Everyone behind you is following me.
네 뒤에 있는 사람들이 다 나를 따라오고 있어.
Hold on bro
잠깐만요 형
can't stop
멈출 수 없어
It's okay, hold on
괜찮아, 잠깐만
The third child
세 번째 아이
Slow down, third child
천천히 해라, 셋째 아이야
Follow behind
뒤를 따라가다
Brother, hold on
형, 잠깐만요
Go
가다
Go quickly
빨리 가세요
Don't forget what I told you
내가 말한 것을 잊지 마세요.
Go
가다
peach girl
복숭아 소녀
I know
알아요
What did I say wrong?
내가 뭘 잘못 말했나요?
What did you say wrong?
무슨 말을 잘못했어요?
Lao Bao told me
라오바오가 나한테 말했어
I know you
나는 당신을 알고
Why are you unhappy?
왜 불행합니까?
It's all my fault for being stupid
멍청한 건 다 내 잘못이야
I can't speak
나는 말을 할 수 없다
Actually I wanted to say that day
사실 그날은 말하고 싶었어
You are kind and kind
당신은 친절하고 친절합니다
you are nice to everyone
당신은 누구에게나 친절해요
I just want to praise you
나는 단지 당신을 칭찬하고 싶습니다
I also know that you are very kind to me
당신이 나에게 매우 친절하다는 것도 알아요
But
하지만
me
나
I still don't seem to have made it clear
아직까지 확실히 밝혀지지 않은 것 같아요
Okay, okay
알았어 알았어
clumsy-tongued
말이 서투른
peach girl
복숭아 소녀
Actually I want to say
사실 내가 하고 싶은 말은
I know you are good to me
나는 당신이 나에게 좋은 줄 알아요
So I also want to be nice to you
그러니까 나도 너한테 잘해주고 싶어
ok i get it
알았어 알겠어
real
진짜
Then you are not angry anymore
그러면 더 이상 화내지 마세요.
You know when you ignore me
네가 언제 나를 무시하는지 알잖아
I feel so bad
기분이 너무 안 좋아
That depends
조건에 따라서
This girl is in a good mood
이 여자 기분이 좋아
Fourth child
넷째 아이
coming
오는
There seems to be the sound of horse hooves
말 발굽 소리가 나는 것 같습니다.
Second child
둘째 아이
You take the third child with you to get away first.
셋째 아이를 데리고 먼저 도망가세요.
Even if I only have one arm
팔이 하나만 있어도
I can still fight
난 아직 싸울 수 있어
This one’s surname is Cui
이 사람 성은 Cui예요.
ungrateful
일한 보람 없는
We kindly rescued
친절하게 구해주셨어요
He and Cui Jiajun
그와 최자준
He is like this
그는 이렇다
Plot against our Zhenxi Army
우리 Zhenxi 군대에 대한 음모
Even if you die in battle today
오늘 전투에서 죽어도
Arrived underground
지하에 도착함
Be an injustice
불의한 자가 되어라
I won't let him go either
나도 그 사람 놔주지 않을 거야
good
좋은
Take the seriously injured brother
중상을 입은 형제를 데리고
Hidden in the woods
숲 속에 숨겨진
The slightly injured brother picked up the weapon
경상을 입은 형제가 무기를 집어 들었다
Follow me to meet the enemy
나를 따라와 적을 만나다
good
좋은
Follow behind everyone
모두 뒤를 따라가세요
Take a walk
산책하다
How about it
어때?
There is a team of people ahead
앞에 한 팀이 있다
suddenly stopped
갑자기 멈췄다
But there aren't many of them
하지만 그 수가 많지는 않아요
I don’t know if it’s an enemy or a friend
적인지 아군인지 모르겠어
Then come forward
그럼 앞으로 나와
Is the enemy
적인가?
Then kill him
그럼 그를 죽여라
okay
좋아요
General Pei
페이 장군
I can fight to the death here with you today
난 오늘 여기서 너와 함께 죽을 때까지 싸울 수 있어
Worth it
그만한 가치가 있어요
Brothers
형제
Bros
브라더스
kill
죽이다
Jushichiro
주시치로
what happened
무슨 일이에요
Aren't you in Aoguan?
당신은 Aoguan에 있지 않습니까?
How come you were so seriously injured?
왜 그렇게 심하게 다쳤나요?
Seventeen Lang, why did you come here?
세븐틴 랑씨, 여기 왜 왔나요?
So many of our brothers died
우리 형제들이 너무 많이 죽었어
Kill this Cui family member
이 Cui 가족을 죽여라
Revenge for the Zhenxi Army
진시군에 대한 복수
kill
죽이다
Brother Zhao
자오 형제
This person
이 사람
own people
자신의 사람들
Cui Jiajun sold Aoguan
Cui Jiajun은 Aoguan을 매각했습니다.
Colluding with Sun Jingli to cooperate with foreigners
외국인과 협력하기 위해 Sun Jingli와 공모
Killed so many brothers
너무 많은 형제를 죽였어
You said she is one of your own
당신은 그녀가 당신 자신의 사람이라고 말했어요
Jushichiro
주시치로
You can't be deceived by her again
다시는 그 사람에게 속으면 안 돼
She and Cui had already planned
그녀와 Cui는 이미 계획을 세웠어요
How many of you
당신은 몇 명입니까?
Deceived to go to West Changjing
속아서 서창징으로 가다
Cui Jiajun is inside Aoguan
Cui Jiajun은 Aoguan 안에 있습니다.
Cooperate with Sun Jingli
Sun Jingli와 협력
Killed so many of our brothers
우리 형제들을 너무 많이 죽였어
Sold Aoguan
판매된 아오관
witch
마녀
I, Pei, are at odds with you.
나 페이는 너랑 반대야.
Aying
아잉
He Xiaowei
허 샤오웨이
This was all planned by you
이건 다 네가 계획한 거야
So you want
그래서 당신은 원한다
Accompany me to Xichangjing
시창징까지 동행해주세요
What can be said to relieve the siege of Yingzhou?
영주의 포위를 완화하려면 어떻게 해야 합니까?
no
아니요
On the way back to Aoguan
아오관으로 돌아가는 길
You said your Cui Jiajun
당신은 Cui Jiajun이라고 말했어요
An army was scattered
군대가 흩어졌다
Need to meet
만나야 해
You know I'm worried
내가 걱정하는 거 알잖아
I will definitely escort you to the rendezvous.
약속 장소까지 꼭 안내해 드리겠습니다.
But in fact, this is to lure the tiger away from the mountain
그러나 사실 이것은 호랑이를 산에서 멀리 유인하기 위한 것이다.
Just to delay me
단지 나를 지연시키려고
Don't let me go back to Aoguan
나를 아오관(Aoguan)으로 돌아가게 하지 마세요
I said I had no idea
나는 전혀 모른다고 말했다
Don’t you want to believe it?
믿고 싶지 않으세요?
Jushichiro
주시치로
You can't trust her anymore
당신은 더 이상 그녀를 믿을 수 없습니다
From confrontation to now
대결부터 지금까지
How many times has she lied to you?
그녀는 당신에게 몇 번이나 거짓말을 했나요?
Jushichiro
주시치로
She has tricked you so many times
그녀는 당신을 여러 번 속였습니다
Do you still believe her?
아직도 그녀를 믿나요?
you don't know
당신은 모른다
I Zhenxijun
나 젠시준
So many brothers died
너무 많은 형제들이 죽었어
Isn’t it your Cui Jiajun?
당신의 Cui Jiajun 아닌가요?
Did it happen with Sun Jing?
Sun Jing에게 그런 일이 일어났나요?
Since you don't want to believe it
당신은 그것을 믿고 싶지 않기 때문에
Then I can't argue
그럼 난 반박할 수 없어
How can I trust you?
내가 너를 어떻게 믿어?
You are your master’s best friend
당신은 주인의 가장 친한 친구입니다
Such a big thing
이런 큰 일이라니
He won't discuss it with you
그 사람은 당신과 그것에 대해 논의하지 않을 것입니다
first acquaintance
첫 만남
I did plot against you
내가 당신을 반대할 음모를 꾸몄어요
but this time
하지만 이번에는
I really don't
난 정말 그렇지 않아
Outside Aoguan
아오관 외곽
We saved you and Cui Jiajun
우리는 당신과 Cui Jiajun을 구했습니다
How can you
어떻게 할 수 있니?
Do this to our Zhenxi Army
우리 진시군에게 이렇게 해주세요
stop
멈추다